MATTHEW CRITELLI

■ matthew.critelli@gmail.com♥ mattcritelli.github.io/portfolio

(929)387-6652

P Denver, Colorado, USA

in mattcritelli

nattcritelli 🕜

SUMMARY

Driven software engineer excited for an opportunity to grow and expand my technical skill-set across the stack. Excellent communicator who thrives equally in a collaborative environment as well as when working independently. Prior management experience ensures I take ownership of my work and always deliver as promised.

SKILLS

LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORKS: Ruby, Rails, Javascript (ES6), HTML, CSS, ¡Query, React, NodeJS, Express

METHODOLOGIES: Agile development, Test-driven development, Object-Oriented Programming

DATABASES: Postgres, MongoDB

CORE: Git/Version Control, Bash/CLI, Heroku

EXPERIENCE

REACTUAL
Junior Software Engineer (Contract)

Denver, CO Sep 2017 to Jan 2018

- Created pixel-perfect React styled-components based on design team sketch files
- Implemented back-end migration of business users and support tickets from Groove legacy software to ZenDesk through API using Javascript ES6, NodeJS, MongoDB, and third-party libraries
- Gained significant experience pair-programming and debugging, also worked independently which required a high-degree of resourcefulness to hit project deadlines

TOURISM IRELAND

New York, NY Feb 2015 to Jul 2016

Digital Marketing Executive

- Led planning and execution of digital marketing campaigns within the U.S. market (SEM, display, third-party content marketing, website content development) to achieve corporate goals and objectives
- · Created advertising campaigns with agencies and vendors aligned with brand objectives and market research
- Analyzed campaign performance and presented learnings to stakeholders in overseas markets
- Trained junior marketing staff on professional and media-related skills, knowledge, and processes

HORIZON MEDIA

Brand Strategy Supervisor

New York, NY Nov 2012 to Feb 2015

- Managed the development and execution of integrated communications planning including targeting, competitive analysis, strategy development and media investment optimization
- · Conducted media post-campaign analysis and provided insights and recommendations
- Supervised team throughout planning process and established internal direction and priorities

PROJECTS

SWAPPER

Swapper allows you to find fellow remote workers in cities around the world and swap workspaces to save money. Technologies used: NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, PassportJS, and Bootstrap.

RUN2GETHER

A web application that connects runners based on their proximity, experience, and availability. This project was built using the following technologies: Ruby on Rails, Postgres, AJAX, jQuery, Google Maps API, and Materialize.

EDUCATION

DEV BOOTCAMP

Full-Stack Web Development Program 2016

Five month immersive web development program with 1000+ hours of experience covering full-stack technologies Created full-scale web applications using Agile development, MVC pattern architecture, and Heroku deployment

BOSTON UNIVERSITY

B.S. Business Administration 2004

Dean's List Honorary